Samuel Selikoff

11 Bentley St, Brighton, MA 02135 Tel: 321-698-2353 Em: sam.selikoff@gmail.com Github: www.github.com/samselikoff Personal website: www.samselikoff.com

SUMMARY

Technologies

 D3.js, Backbone.js, Ember.js, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JSON API, Twitter Bootstrap, Symfony, Silex, Dojo, MySQL, Git, Tortoise SVN, Apache, Windows, Linux

Languages

- ► JavaScript (1 year)
- ▶ PHP (1 year)
- ▶ Perl (1 year)

Techniques

- ▶ Object-oriented design
- ▶ Test-driven development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer, system admin Intex Solutions, Needham, MA

September 2012 - Present

Full-stack design and development of custom internal web applications

- Pioneered and created a wiki used to share company knowledge and documentation (symfony, mysgl)
- ▶ Built data visualizations to monitor fileserver load, web server speeds, data processing and more (d3, backbone, jquery, mysql)
- Created client surveys and displayed the results in a dynamic report (d3, jquery, mysql)
- Created a site to organize client contracts, reconcile data inconsistencies, and summarize monthly financial data (symfony, ember, d3, mysql)
- ▶ Built a reporting site to show customized dashboards of historical data processing rates, JIRA development tickets and more (d3, ember, mysql)
- Created a system used company-wide to guide development of main product (jquery, json api, perl)

Development, maintenance, and scheduling of Perl scripts for automation and notification

- Monitored web server and database server performance and integrity, internal data processing, and client application use and bottlenecks
- ▶ Alerted team to errors in data processing and other critical operations
- Automated client emails in response to triggers, including custom searches and expiring licenses
- ▶ Scheduled nightly downloads from various third-party data providers
- Automated the maintenance of modules, configuration settings, and other files across internal servers

Maintenance of internal file, database, and web server infrastructure

- Designed, managed and optimized MySQL databases used internally and externally
- ▶ Maintained complex database arrangement with multiple levels of redundancy, slaving and backup
- ▶ Various tasks on Linux web servers, including installing and updating PHP/Perl source and modules, and maintaining Apache

Analyst Cornerstone Research, Boston, MA

January 2012 - August 2012

- ▶ Supported companies in litigation involving complex financial and economic issues
- Wrote programs to import, manipulate and display queried data using SAS / MySQL
- ▶ Created VBA macro for Excel that incorporated JavaScript and HTML to automatically import PHP-requested data from a website to a spreadsheet
- ▶ Created a dynamic, interactive Excel worksheet using VBA to automate a routine data request
- ▶ Created a VBA macro for Excel to automate standard chart formatting
- Co-formed 'Innovation Committee' to organize and maintain a firm-wide repository of useful macros, code snippets and functions
- Drafted and edited expert reports used in corporate litigation

EXPERIENCE

ENTREPRENEURIAL Co-Founder/CEO Streable LLC, Boulder, CO

June 2011 - September 2011

- ▶ Raised \$7,000 for preliminary development of an innovative online commenting system
- Created a recruiting video successfully used to hire two software developers
- ▶ Wrote a business plan to guide company

Co-Founder/CEO Gator Tutoring LLC, Gainesville, FL

June 2008 - May 2010

- ▶ Formed online tutoring company serving University of Florida business students
- Learned Adobe After Effects, Illustrator and Photoshop to enhance quality of tutoring content
- Earned over \$20,000 in revenue from sale of online products
- Developed, produced and sold over 250 videos and hundreds of pages of notes for six classes
- Approached by economics professor to use company's written materials in class
- ▶ Pioneered innovative low-cost software technique to produce videos more efficiently

EDUCATION Boston College Chestnut Hill, MA

December 2011

M.A. in Economics

► GPA 3.75/4.0, graduate stipend, research assistantship

University of Florida Gainesville, FL

May 2009

B.S. in Business Administration, Finance

▶ GPA 3.90/4.0, Magna Cum Laude, Minor in Chinese, Dean's List, President's List

OTHER

Teaching, public speaking

- ▶ Taught live GRE/GMAT prep courses through Kaplan
- ▶ Extensive TA and tutoring experience from undergraduate/graduate school, Gator Tutoring

Design

▶ Adobe Illustrator, After Effects, Photoshop